S. Guy Endore papers, 1925-1970
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Guy Endore's Participation for the Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee
  - Isserman, Abraham J., (3 items) (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Letter to Lev Gleason, Gleason Publications, New York., April 17, 1944; (1 item. Typescript carbon) (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - McGrath, Alice. Letters to Guy Endore., (4 items) (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - July 3, 1944., (1 item) (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - July 7, 1944., (1 item) (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - August 1, 1944., (1 item) (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Letter, 1944 October 25, Los Angeles, California to Guy Endore, (1 item: 3pp., typed letter signed) (Box 83, Folder 8)
      With detailed account of dismissal of the Sleepy Lagoon case.
      Alice recounts the events of the defendants release from jail.
  - Sleepy Lagoon defendants. Letter, 1944 July 23, to Mr. Guy Endore, (1 item: 2pp.) (Box 83, Folder 9)
    Letter thanks Endore for all of his help in their defense, especially for writing "The Sleepy Lagoon Mystery". Signed: The Sleepy Lagoon Defendants.
- Books from the Library of Guy Endore
  - Books from Guy Endore's library, all re Balzac (Boxes 33-35)
    - 12 volumes (Box 33)
    - 9 volumes (Box 34)
    - 9 volumes (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous books from the library of Guy Endore (Boxes 36-38)
    - 10 volumes (Box 36)
    - 15 volumes (Box 37)
    - 12 volumes (Box 38)
  - Gover, Robert. The Portable Walter. From The Prose And Poetry Of Walter Lowenfels. New York: International Publishers., 1968; (160pp. Paperback) (Box 83)
    Inscription from Walter Lowenfels on half-title page.
  - Endore, Guy. Voltaire! Voltaire! New York: Simon and Schuster., 1961; (507pp. Paperback. Lacking cover) (Box 83)
    This copy has been edited by Guy Endore for the London edition (W.H. Allen, 1962). Portions of the text have been deleted, chapters renumbered, and a few additions have been made.
  - Sanford, John. The People From Heaven. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company., 1943; (232pp. With dustjacket) (Box 83)
    Inscribed by the author on front flyleaf.
  - Caspary, Vera. The Weeping And The Laughter. Boston: Little, Brown and Company., 1950; (301pp. Lacking dustjacket) (Box 83)
    Inscribed by the author on flyleaf following title page.
  - Bessie, Alvah. Bread And A Stone. New York: Modern Age Books., 1941; (346pp. Lacking dustjacket) (Box 83)
    Inscribed by the author on the title page.
- Legal Documents, 1923-1956
  - Includes Seaman's Certificate of American Citizenship., May 25, 1923; (7 items) (Box 83)
- War Service, 1942
  - Correspondence and documents re Endore's applications for service in the First Motion Picture Unit and Office of Strategic Services., (18 items) (Box 83)
- Correspondence
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - A - Be. (Box 72)
    American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU). Southern California
    American Federation of Labor-Committee for Industrial Organization (AFL-CIO). Industrial Union Department. Washington, D.C.
    Abbott, Richard.
    Abel (Richard) & Company Portland, Oregon.
    Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. Hollywood, California
    Adams & Company, Limited Florence, Italy.
    Adler, Stella.
    Adler, Steve.
    Agins, J.
    Albert, Chas. d'
    Aline Marie, Sister.
    Allen (W.H.) & Company London.
    Amat, Jean-Marie d'.
    American Friends Service Committee. Pasadena, California
    American Museum of Natural History. New York.
    American Printing House for the Blind. Louisville, Kentucky.
    American Society for Psychical Research, Incorporated New York.
    Ames, Elizabeth.
    Ansen, Joseph.
    Anti-Imperialist League. New York.
    Apotheker, Nan.
    Arbeiter. New York.
    Arens, Egmont.
    Arnold, Edward. (Publishers) Limited London.
    Arnold, Aerol & Anna (Bing).
    Arnold, P.M.
    Arthur, Robert.
    Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, Incorporated Washington, D.C.
    Atlanta University. Atlanta, Georgia.
    Authors Guild of the Authors League of America, Incorporated New York.
    Bachrach, David J.
    Baeck (Leo) Temple. Los Angeles.
    Baker, Mary.
    Ball, Dianne.
    Baltzer, Alvin W.
    Bank for Foreign Trade U.S.S.R. Moscow.
    Bank of America. Burbank, California
    Bank of Canada. Montreal.
    Bar-David Literary Agency. Tel Aviv, Israel.
    Barbe, Muriel Culp.
    Barlin, Paul and Anna.
    Barneveld (van) & Ellis Public Relations. Santa Ana, California
    Barnsdall, Aline.
    Barquet, Nicolas.
    Barry, Ada.
    Barry, Frederick E.
    Barzman, Ben and Norma.
    Bautzer & Grant. Beverly Hills, California
    Bazelis, Robert.
    Becker, Florence.
    Beebe, Lucius
    Beerman, Leonard I.
    Behr, Nicholas.
    Behrman (H.J. & M.H.) Company. New York.
    Behrman, Jane.
    Behrstock, Albert.
    Belfrage, Cedric & Mary.
    Belt, Elmer.
    Benacenaf, Mersedes Herrera de.
    Benedict, Laszlo.
    Bengal, Ben.
    Bentley, Eric.
    Benzion, Alexander.
    Berckmans, Fr.
    Bercovici, Leonardo.
    Bercovici, Rion.
    Berghoff, Emanuel.
    Bernstein, Hazel Moore.
    Bessie, Alvah & Mary.
    Bessie, Alvah and Sylviane.
    Besterman, Theodore.
    Beverly Hills, California City Hall.
  - Bi - Cl. (Box 73)
    Biberman, Herbert.
    Billings, Warren K.
    Bishop, Paul Byron.
    Bister, John.
    Black, Helen.
    Blanke, Henry.
    Blennerhasset, L.J.
    Blodgett, E. Wright.
    Blue Ribbon Books. New York.
    Blumenthal, William R.
    Bobbs Merrill Company Incorporated Indianapolis, Indiana
    Bodeen, DeWitt.
    Bohli, Marcel.
    Book Find Club. New York.
    Book and Authors Club. Hollywood.
    Book of the Month Club. New York.
    Books Abroad. Norman, Oklahoma.
    Booth, Charles G.
    Borgese, Elisabeth Mann.
    Borsodi, Mr.
    Boston University. Boston, Massachusetts
    Bottiglia, William F.
    Boucher, Anthony.
    Boullet, Jean.
    Bradbury, Ray.
    Branch, Melville.
    Brand, Millen.
    Brandeis University. Waltham, Massachusetts.
    Braus, Mort and Ann.
    Braverman, Harry & Sylvia.
    Brenner, Anita.
    Britten, Onetamae.
    Broffman, Joseph V.
    Bronston (Samuel) Productions Limited London.
    Bronston, Sam.
    Brown University. Providence, Rhode Island.
    Brown, Alfred.
    Brown, George and Allen.
    Brown, Phil.
    Buchman, Sidney.
    Burroughs, Steve.
    Burton, Val.
    Calderone, Mary S.
    California Citizens' Committee on Mental Hygiene Incorporated Los Angeles.
    California Librarian. Pasadena, California.
    Cameron, Angus.
    Carlyle House, Publishers. New York.
    Casanova. Booksellers and Importers. Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
    Casey, Walter T.
    Castagna, Mr.
    Casterline, Sarah.
    Cator, Sylvia P.
    Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. Santa Barbara.
    Cesana, Anne.
    Chalfant, W.A.
    Chambers, Whittaker.
    Chambrun (Jacques), Incorporated New York.
    Chapman, Marista.
    Charwat, Halina.
    Chernoff, Howard L.
    Chicago Jewish Forum. Chicago.
    Children's Book Council. New York.
    Childs, J. Rives.
    Churchill, Judith Chase.
    Clairmonte, Glenn.
    Clarke, Mary.
    Clasen, H.E.
    Clune, Frank
  - Co - Far. (Box 74)
    Colbron, Grace Israel.
    Collier's. New York.
    Colman, Louis.
    Colombian Steamship Company. New York.
    Columbia University. New York.
    Companhia Editora Nacional. Sao Paulo, Brazil.
    Cortez, Ruben.
    Corwin, Norman.
    Costain, Thomas B.
    Council of Jewish Students. Los Angeles.
    Covici, Pascal.
    Crichton, Kyle.
    Critchley, MacDonald.
    Crowley, Francis J.
    Crown Publishers, Incorporated New York.
    Curtis-Brown Limited New York.
    Daily News. Los Angeles.
    Darneal, W.H.
    Dartiquenave, Lys.
    Day (John) Company, Incorporated, Publishers. New York.
    Dekoven, Daniel (4 folders)
    Deutsch, Albert.
    Deutsche Zentralbuchhandlung. New York.
    Dial Press. New York.
    Dick, Hugh.
    Diehl, Valida and Harry.
    Dimitroff, James Stephan.
    Discussion Unlimited. Los Angeles.
    Dock, George.
    Doubleday & Company Incorporated New York.
    Doubleday & Company, Incorporated, Publishers. New York.
    Douglas, Kirk.
    Dreher, Carl and Rose.
    Dreiser, Theodore and Helen.
    Dublin, Leda.
    Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Incorporated New York.
    Durant, Will.
    Durante, Gustave.
    Eames, Charles and Ray.
    Ebenstein, Morris.
    Edelman, Joseph.
    Edmiston, Jim.
    Eisenbach, Robert and Liz.
    Eliasen, Sara H.
    Ellis, Laura M.
    Endore, Mark.
    Equitable Life Assurance. Los Angeles.
    Esquire. New York.
    Etc. Mill Valley, California.
    Evans, Berger.
    Evans, Eve.
    Evans, Ray.
    Exiled Writers Committee. New York.
    Fadiman, Clifton.
    Fadiman, William.
    Fanelli, Henry C.
    Fantl, Kurt.
    Farrart & Rinehart, Incorporated. New York
  - Fas - Ing. (Box 75)
    Fassen, Neal.
    Fellowship of Reconciliation. Nyack, New York.
    Feuchtwanger, Marta.
    Finkelpearl, Henry.
    Fireman's Fund. Santa Ana, California.
    First Unitarian Church. Los Angeles.
    Flamm, Irving H.
    Fleischer, Richard and Mickey.
    Florence, White.
    Flower, Desmond.
    Foreign publishers. (Not England).
    Fortune. New York.
    Fox, James M.
    Freedomways. New York.
    Freund, Karl.
    Friedberg, A.S.
    Friedman, Lawrence J.
    Fritchman, Stephen H.
    Frontier. Los Angeles.
    Frye, Peter.
    Fuller, Lester.
    Gaer, Joseph.
    Gassner, John.
    Geffen, Harold David.
    George, George L. and Elaine.
    Gian-Cursio, Christopher.
    Gideons International. Chicago.
    Glidden, Mary.
    Goldfarb, Robert.
    Goldstein (Sam S.) Industries Incorporated
    Goldstone (Nat C.) Agency.
    Gomberg, Sy.
    Goodwin, Ruby Berkeley.
    Gordon, Arthur.
    Gordon, Bernard.
    Gordon, Don and Henrie.
    Gordon, Eugene.
    Gow, Olga.
    Grafton, Samuel.
    Granoff, Vladimir.
    Grant, Harry.
    Graziotte, Ugo Adriano.
    Greenberg: Publisher. New York.
    Greenson, Diana.
    Greenwood Reprint Corporation. New York.
    Griesbach, George A.
    Griffith, Beatrice.
    Grudin, Morris.
    Hacker Foundation. Beverly Hills, California.
    Hackett, Frances and Albert.
    Halevy, Julian.
    Hall (W.F.) Printing Company Chicago, Illinois
    Halliday, Richard.
    Hammond, Emmy.
    Hand, Wayland D.
    Hannagan (Steve) Publicity. Hollywood and New York.
    Harburg, E. Y.
    Harmon, Sidney.
    Harper & Brothers. New York.
    Harper & Row, Publishers. New York.
    Harrison, Sally.
    Harvard School of Dental Medicine. Boston, Massachusetts
    Hauptfinanzamf fuer Erbschaftsteuer und Verkehrsteurern. Berlin.
    Hayakawa Shobo. Tokyo.
    Hayes, Margot.
    Heeckeren (M. & C.) D'Anthes De.
    Herskovits, Melville J.
    Hicks, Granville.
    Hillel Council. Los Angeles.
    Hinden, R.
    Hofeld, Lorraine.
    Hoffman, Calvin.
    Holiday. New York.
    Holland, Vyvyan.
    Hollywood Reporter. Hollywood.
    Hollywood Writers' Mobilization. Hollywood.
    Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Incorporated New York.
    Howard, Cy.
    Howe, Sanora Babb.
    Howson, Mr.
    Huebsch, Beatrice Huebsch.
    Hughes, Langston.
    Inge, William
  - Ins - Kuh. (Box 76)
    Institut et Musee Voltaire. Geneve.
    Institute for Philosophical Research. San Francis Company
    Inter Books Incorporated New York.
    International Relief Association Incorporated New York.
    Irvine, Gladys.
    Isaacs, Elsie Gold.
    Israel, Jerry.
    Ives, Helen.
    Jackell, Liz.
    Jacobs, Irving. L.
    Jacobs, Lewis.
    Jaffe (Sam) Agency with Mary Baker. Hollywood.
    Jarvis, Al.
    Jelliffe, Belinda.
    Jenson, Ana and Lee[?]
    Jewish Agency. Jerusalem.
    Johnson, L.F.A.
    Jones, John T.
    Jones, Proctor.
    Josephson, Matthew.
    Judge. n.p. (magazine).
    Kahn, Gordon and Barbara.
    Kainz, Franz and Gretl.
    Kantor, James R. K.
    Kaplan, Abbott and Bea.
    Kaplan, Bernard.
    Kaplanski, Boris.
    Kartyshai, Robert.
    Karzmar, Leonard.
    Katz, Charles and Vesta.
    Katz, Charles.
    Katz, Otto and Ilse.
    Kauer, Valerie.
    Kaufman, A.
    Kaufman, Louis and Annette.
    Kaufman, Milton.
    Keats, Mark.
    Keller, Helen.
    Kempner, Alex.
    Kendall (Claude). Publisher. New York.
    King Brothers Productions. Los Angeles.
    Kirstein, Elinor.
    Kisch, Egon Erwin.
    Klein, Arnold.
    Klein, Herbert Arthur.
    Kline, Herbert.
    Klonsky, Bob.
    Knittel, Robert.
    Knopf (Afred A.), Incorporated New York.
    Knudsen, Vern and Florence.
    Kropotkin, Alexanra.
    Kruif, Paul de.
    Kuhn, Franz
  - Lac - Met. (Box 77)
    Laclos, Michel.
    Ladies' Home Journal. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    Landon, Joe.
    Larsson, Kerstin.
    Larsson, R.E.K.
    Lasky, Bessie.
    Last Word. New York.
    Lattimore, Owen.
    League of American Writers. n.p.
    League of Struggle for Negro Rights. New York.
    Lees, Jean.
    Leman, Janne and Anne.
    Levy, Ernest.
    Lewin, Albert.
    Ley, Willy, Olga and Sandra.
    Librairie Delamain & Boutelleau. Paris.
    Librairie Georges Cres & Cie. Paris.
    Library of Congress. Washington, D.C.
    Lichtig-Englander, Agency. Hollywood, California
    Lieker, Herbert.
    Life. New York.
    Limited Editions Club. New York.
    Linder, Eugene.
    Literary Clipping Service.
    Loeb and Loeb. Los Angeles.
    Loewen, M. (Sanni) and Kathe.
    Lomax, Louis E.
    Long, Haniel.
    Longstaff, Alex.
    Loomis, Battell.
    Los Angeles Civic Light Opera Association. Los Angeles.
    Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles.
    Los Angeles. Office of Price Administration.
    Louisiana State University Press. Baton Rouge, La.
    Lowenfels, Walter and Lillian.
    Lubin, Ronald A. and Shulamith.
    Lundberg, Dan.
    MD. New York.
    MGA Incorporated New York.
    Mabbott, Thomas O.
    MacDonald, Andrew.
    Macy, Helen.
    Magazine of Fantasy. New York.
    Magidoff, Isidor.
    Magidoff, Robert.
    Mainstream. New York.
    Malkine, Fern.
    Maltz, Albert.
    Maltz, Harry.
    Maltz, Maxwell.
    Manas. Los Angeles.
    Mann, Thomas.
    Margolis, Ben.
    Marian, Paul.
    Marks, Richard Lee.
    Marmelzat, Willard Lee.
    Marmor, Judd.
    Marti-Ibanez, Felix.
    Martin, Jay.
    Martin, Liberty.
    Marton (George) Plays.
    Marz, Zeppo.
    Mason, Pamela.
    Mate, Mrs.
    Maxon, Constance M.
    McClellan, Don.
    McComas, J. Francis.
    McEachen, James.
    McFarland, Jeannette.
    McKay (David) Company, Incorporated New York.
    McTernan, John T.
    McWilliams, Carey.
    Medlock, Julie.
    Meltcalfe, Evelyn Scott.
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures. Culver City, California
    Metz, Jules
  - Mic - Ran. (Box 78)
    Michel, Joe
    Milburn, George & Vivien
    Miller, Gail C.
    Miller, Lee
    Miller, Loren
    Miller, Louis
    Mindlin, Eugene and Martha
    Mischel, Florence
    Mitchell, Norma
    Mittler, Leo
    Modesto, Zapata
    Monaster, Nate
    Monthly Review. New York
    Morales, Henry
    Morley, Sophia
    Morris (William) Agency, Incorporated Beverly Hills, California
    Morris, Ruth
    Morris, William and Elizabeth
    Morrison, Lester
    Mosk, Edward
    Mostel, Zero
    Motion Picture Relief Fund. Hollywood, California
    Mumford, Lewis
    Muni, Paul
    Mystery Writers of America, Incorporated New York
    Nation. New York
    Needham, Wilbur
    New Jersey. State Board of Health
    New Masses. New York
    New Republic. New York
    New Theatre League. New York
    New York Evening Post. New York
    New York Herald Tribune. New York
    New York Times Book Review. New York
    News. Dallas, Texas
    Newsweek. New York
    Nichols, Dudley
    Nolan, Edward D.
    Norman, Charles
    Norman, Theodore and Ruth
    North, Joe
    Oberdorfer, Richard
    Ohio Superstitutions Project. Western Reserve University. Cleveland
    Ornitz, Sam and Sadie
    Overseas News Agency, Incorporated New York
    Pacific Coast Claim Adjusters. Los Angeles
    Pacifica Foundation. Berkeley and Los Angeles
    Paramount Pictures Incorporated Hollywood, California
    Pasternak, Joseph
    Pattee, Richard
    Payot. Paris
    Pearce, Charles A.
    People's World. n.p.
    Perkins, Cliff
    Phillips, Gifford
    Pickwick Bookshops. Hollywood, California
    Pierpont Morgan Library. New York
    Polonsky, Abraham and Sylvia
    Pomerance, Bill
    Pratt, Gerald H.
    Preminger, Ingo
    Presence du Cinema. Paris
    Presnell, Robert
    Producer-Writers Guild of America Pension Plan. Los Angeles
    Progressive Citizens of America. Southern California Chapter. Hollywood
    Protestant Chaplaincy of Bellevue Hospital. New York
    Putnam's (G.P.) Sons. New York
    RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated Los Angeles
    Radin, Doris
    Radovic, Ljerka
    Rady, Lillian
    Rains, Claude
    Random House. New York
  - Rea - Simm. (Box 79)
    Reader's Digest. New York
    Register of Copyrights. Washington, D.C.
    Reinhardt, Wolfgang
    Reis (Bernard) & Company. New York
    Renova, Anne
    Reproductive Physiology Research and Training Center. Mexico City
    Republic Productions, Incorporated North Hollywood, California
    Resner, Herbert
    Restaurant Associates, Incorporated New York
    Resthaven, Incorporated Los Angeles
    Reuben, William A.
    Ribeiro, Luis Jose Bonito
    Rigler, L.E.
    Rinehart & Company, Incorporated New York
    Rissient, Pierre
    Roberson, Doris B.W.
    Robinson, Edward G.
    Roden, Jane
    Rodgers, Belinda (Mrs. John)
    Rolling, Marie
    Rose Pastor Stokes Rest Home. New York
    Rosenbloom, Samuel
    Ross, James
    Ross, Liebe
    Rossen, Robert
    Rotstein, Janet Stevenson
    Roumain, Jacques
    Rover Motor Company of North America, Limited South San Francisco, California
    Ruben, Albert
    Ruby, Harry
    Russell, Thomas
    Sainte Colombe, Paul de
    Salt, Waldo
    Samoussoud, Clara Clemens
    Sanford, John
    Santana Pictures. Hollywood
    Saturday Evening Post. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    Saturday Review. New York
    Schary, Dore
    Schloss, Malcolm
    Schneer, Jacob B.
    Schneider, Isidor
    Schwartz, Hanns
    Schwartz, Howard
    Science & Society. New York
    Scott, Thurston
    Screen Writers' Guild. Hollywood, California
    Seabrook, William
    Segal, Allen M.
    Selden, Mr.
    Seltzer, Adele Szold
    Sesit, Myron
    Seven Arts Associated Corporation New York
    Seven Seas Books. Berlin
    Shallit, A.B.
    Shapiro, Samuel S.
    Shaw, Barnett
    Shelton, Herbert M.
    Sherman, David E.
    Sherman, Harold
    Sherman, Solomon
    Sieroty, Jean
    Silvers, Maurice
    Simmel, Ernest
    Skadron, Bernard
    Sklar, George
    Sklar, Zachary
    Sloan, N.P.
  - Smi - Vos. (Box 80)
    Smirnoff, Victor
    Smith, Francis
    Smith, Hal
    Smith, Henry Nash
    Smith, Jack
    Smith, John and Lucille
    Smith, Lillian
    Solomon, Lou and Wilma
    Sophian, Minna
    Spencer, D.A.
    Spingarn, Lawrence P.
    Stark, Ray
    Steele, Joseph Henry
    Steinmetz, Fred H.
    Sterling, Wallace
    Stern, Virginia
    Steuben, Fritzie
    Stevenson, Janet M.
    Stewart, Rosalie
    Stillman, David
    Stoller, A.L.
    Stoller, M.
    Stoller, Robert
    Stone, I.F.
    Stone, Leo
    Stranger, Lynn
    Strawn, Arthur
    Studies on the Left. Madison, Wisconsin
    Sullivan, Edward S.
    Sun. New York
    Sussman, Aaron
    Taggard, Genevieve
    Tarchetti, Lucille Ostrow
    Time. New York
    Tiomkin, Dimitri
    Titelman, Leonard and Lory
    Tobey, Berkeley
    Toch, Lily
    Today's Woman. New York
    Tolnai, B.
    Trivas, Victor,
    Trumbo, Dalton
    Tsei, Loh
    Turkson, Y.B.
    Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation. Beverly Hills, California
    U.S. Consul General. Stuttgart
    U.S.S.R. Consul General. Washington, D.C.
    United French Publishers. Paris and New York
    Universal Studios. Universal City, California
    University of California, Berkeley. Extension
    University of California, Los Angeles. Library
    University of California, Los Angeles. Office of the Chancellor
    University of California, Los angeles. Extension
    University of California. School of Library Science
    University of Chicago Library. Chicago
    University of Judaism. Los Angeles
    University of Massachusetts. Amherst
    University of Texas, Austin. Department of Sociology
    Valenti, Jack
    Valli, Jake and Shirley
    Van Veen, Stuyvesant
    Vanguard. Los Angeles
    Vargha, Marila K.
    Venable, Emerson
    Verde Valley School. Sedona, Arizona
    Veritas Film. Cambridge, Massachusetts
    Village Voice. New York
    Vorhaus, Bernard
    Vosper, Robert
  - Wac - Zab. (Box 81)
    Wachsman (R.A.) Company Oxnard, California
    Wachsman, Rhea
    Wallace, William
    Walsh, Donald E.
    Walter, Mildred
    Wanger (Walter) Productions, Incorporated Hollywood, California
    Warfel, Harry
    Warner Brothers. Burbank, California
    Warren, Hamilton
    Warren, Leon H.
    Watkins (Ann), Incorporated New York
    Watson, Douglas
    Wayne, June
    Weddell, J.P.
    Weiner, Joseph
    Weiss, Walter A.
    Wellcome Historial Medical Museum. London
    Welton, Elise
    Wertenbaker, Charles
    Westside Jewish Community Center. Los Angeles
    Wexley, John
    White, Morris and Irene
    Whittlesley House. San Francisco and New York
    Wibberley, Leonard
    Wiener, Lily
    Wilkinson, Laurence and Louise
    Willey, Robert A.
    Wills, Margaret Bennett
    Winter, Ella Stewart
    With, Gerda
    Wollheim, Donald A.
    Women Strike for Peace. Los Angeles
    Worthing, John
    Wright, Ernest
    Writers Guild of America, West, Incorporated Los Angeles
    Y.W.C.A. New York
    Yale University. New Haven, Connecticut
    Young & Rubicam, Incorporated, Hollywood
    Young, Elizabeth (Mrs. Nedrick)
    Young, Jack
    Zablodowsky, David and Gen
  - Zei -. (Box 82)
    Zeiler, Floria
    Zeitlin, Jake
    Zeligs, Meyer A.
    Zemach, Benjamin
- [Miscellaneous] Correspondence
  - Malcolm, Cowley (Box 74)
  - Indiana University. Bloomington, Indiana (Box 76)
  - Mogensen, Carol Warren (Box 77)
  - St. Martin's Press. New York (Box 79)
  - Willner (George) Associates Agency. New York (Box 80)
  - Unidentified., (5 folders) (Box 82)
  - Decker, Rubin (Box 84)
  - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 85)
    Ellis, Robert
    Endore, Celia (2 folders)
    Endore, Gita
  - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 86)
    Endore, Marcia
    Endore, Mark and Gita
    Robin, Eva
    Stollers, Adelyn
  - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 87)
    Contracts
    Cooper (Frank) Associates Agency, Incorporated New York and Hollywood
    Cooper - Goldfarb - Jaffe
    Curtis Publishing Company Philadelphia
    Doff, Jerome L.
    Duell, Charles
    Faragoh, Francis and Elizabeth
    Fonda, Henry
    Gollancz (Victor) Limited London
    Little, Brown and Company. Boston
    Royalty statements
  - Simon and Schuster, Incorporated. New York., 1936, 1955-1964 (Box 88)
  - Vanguard Press. New York (Box 88)
  - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 89)
    Fleishman, Stanley
    Western Printing and Lithographing Company Racine, Wisconsin Ben-Hur
    Western Printing and Lithographing Company Racine, Wisconsin Frank Taylor
  - Fles, Barthold., 1949-1970 (Boxes 81, 89-90)
    - 1969-1970. (Box 81)
    - 1949-1954. (Box 89)
    - 1955-1968. (Box 90)